Guide to the Joan Jacobs Brumberg papers,1980-2014.
Brumberg, Joan Jacobs papers
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Joan Jacobs Brumberg papers, 1980-2014.
23-3-3151
Joan Jacobs. Brumberg
14.5 cubic ft.
Audio Recordings,Correspondence, Research Materials, Newspapers, Printed Materials
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Correspondence, articles, lectures, and subject files pertaining to Brumberg's career, her research on the history of home economics and her books: Mission for Life; Fasting Girls: the Emergence of Anorexia Nervosa as a Modern Disease; The Body Project: An Intimate History of American Girls; and Kansas Charley: the Story of a Nineteenth Century Boy Murderer.
BIOGRAPHICAL NOTE
Professor of Human Development, Cornell University.
Brumberg received her bachelor's degree in history from the University of Rochester in 1965, her master's degree in American studies from Boston College in 1971 and her doctoral degree in American history from the University of Virginia in 1978. She has served on the Cornell faculty since 1979 and was director of the Women's Studies Program from 1985 to 1988.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Correspondence, articles, lectures, and subject files pertaining to Brumberg's career, her research on the history of home economics and her books: Mission for Life; Fasting Girls: the Emergence of Anorexia Nervosa as a Modern Disease; The Body Project: An Intimate History of American Girls; and Kansas Charley: the Story of a Nineteenth Century Boy Murderer.
Boxes 1-3 and 13-14 contain correspondence and subject files concerning the various books written by Joan.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Brumberg, Joan Jacobs.; Brumberg, Joan Jacobs.; Miller, Charley, 1874-1892.; Cornell University--Faculty.; New York State College of Human Ecology.Dept. of Human Development.
Subjects:
Body, Human--Social aspects--United States--History.; Juvenile delinquency--United States.; Capital punishment--United States.; Young women--United States--History.; Murders--United States; Teenage girls--United States--History.; Anorexia nervosa.; Home economics--Study and teaching.; Home economics--History.
Form and Genre Terms:
Videotapes .; Compact disks.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
Access Restrictions:
Boxes 1-3, 14-15 are closed until 2038 except by permission of the donor.
SERIES LIST
Series I. Biographical
Series II. Correspondence
Series III. Lectures
Series IV. Teaching Material
Series V. Correspondence, Background Research, Publicity, Book Reviews, Pertaining to the Books Written by Joan
Series VI. Papers, Articles, Book Reviews, Grants by Joan
Series VII. Articles, Book Reviews, Written About Joan and/or her Work
Series VIII. Conferences, Lecture Series, Workshops Organized by Joan
Series IX. Audio-Visual Material
CONTAINER LIST
- Series I. Biographical
  - Awards, 1988-2000 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Warren Center Fellowship - Harvard, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Third year review, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Research statement, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Third year review concerning women's studies appointment, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Course on anorexia nervosa - Harvard, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Rockefeller Foundation Humanities Fellowship - " A Social and Cultural History of Anorexia Nervosa", 1984-03 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Sabbatical information, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Promotion to full professor file, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Interview of Joan - German publication (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Board of Directors - New York Council for the Humanities (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Film "The Famine Within", 1990 (Box 4, Folder 12)
    Includes interview of Joan
  - Exhibit interpreter - "Outsiders All: 19th Century Prisons, Mental Hospitals and Asylums", 1990-05 (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Fellow in the history of obstetrics and gynecology, 1990-1991 (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Guggenheim Fellowship, 1990-1992 (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - National Endowment for the Humanities Fellow, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Conference on New York State History, 1991-06 (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Consultant - "A Troop of Tomboys", 1991 (Box 4, Folder 18)
  - Consultant - " America Eats Out", 1991 (Box 4, Folder 19)
  - Mann Fellowship, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 20)
  - MacDowell Residency, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 21)
  - MacDowell Residency, 2001 (Box 4, Folder 22)
  - Renfrew Center - keynote speaker, 1995-05 (Box 4, Folder 23)
  - Fulbright - University of Otago, New Zealand, 1995-06-1995-08 (Box 4, Folder 24)
  - Consultant film - "Typhoid Mary ", 1996 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Moderator - "Berkshire Conference on the History of Women", 1996-06 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Advisory Board - Teen People, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - Stephen H Weiss Presidential Fellow Award, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Doshisha University Residency, 1997 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Review of Maryland Science Center Exhibit, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Photographs (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Consultant - migrant exhibit, 1998 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Connecticut Women's Hall of Fame (exhibit on female body image), 1999 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Panel discussion on Hillary Clinton, 2000 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Sandy Bem, 1979 (Box 4, Folder 35)
  - Nancy Tomes, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 36)
  - Faye Dudden, 1981-1982 (Box 4, Folder 37)
  - Local research, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 38)
  - Conference notes: Seneca Falls 1850 v Female Adolescents 1982, Barnard Adolescent Conference, 1983-02 (Box 4, Folder 39)
  - Caroline Bynum, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Joe Kett, 1982-1983 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Allan Brandt, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - De Prospo, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 43)
  - Glen Elder, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Ken Lockridge, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 44A)
  - Barbara Sicherman, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Judith Walzer leavitt, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Barbara Rosenkrantz, 1983 (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Journal of Social History, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - SSRC workshop - "Great Historical Changes with Consequences for Children", 1984 (Box 4, Folder 51)
  - Maxine Groffsky literary agency agreement, 1985 (Box 4, Folder 52)
  - Sue Lees- North London Polytechnic, 1988 (Box 4, Folder 54)
  - Daniel Walkowitz, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 56)
  - Ellen Jacober Foundation for Eating Disorders, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 57)
  - Editorial board: "Feminist Issues" University Press of Virginia, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 58)
  - Alice Rossi, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 59)
  - American Studies Association - professional ethics, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 60)
  - American Studies Association - national council, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 61)
  - American Studies Association, 1993-11 (Box 4, Folder 62)
  - Professors of large selection committee, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 63)
  - Women's history review, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 64)
  - Judith Zinnser visit- women's history month, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 65)
  - Concerning diaries, 1992-1994 (Box 4, Folder 66)
  - Women's studies - 10th anniversary committee, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 67)
  - Mineke Van Essen visit - women's history month, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 68)
  - Concerning teaching religion and concerning suspected violation of the integrity code, 1993, 1994 (Box 4, Folder 69)
  - University of Rochester - chair in women's studies position, 1993 (Box 4, Folder 70)
  - Sabbatic, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 71)
  - Journal of the History of Sexuality, Bard College, 1993-1995 (Box 4, Folder 72)
  - Jessie Fauset Prize, 1993-1994 (Box 4, Folder 73)
  - Women's history month, 1994-03 (Box 4, Folder 74)
  - Jackie Goldsby, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 75)
  - "Making of America" project, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 76)
  - Advisory board of the Rutgeers University Press series in childhood studies, 2000-2001 (Box 16, Folder 70)
- Series II. Correspondence
  - Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 48)
  - Correspondence, 1983-1984 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Wales correspondence, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - Correspondence, 1990-1999 (Box 4, Folder 55)
  - Catherine Roberts - Harvard Graduate School, 1995-1997 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - New York Women's Encyclopedia, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Women's studies curriculum, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Women's history month, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence concerning The history channel's show on holidays, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Human Development and Family Studies Department review, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Sidney and Frances Jacobs Book Fund For American History, Cornell Library, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Questionnaire Random House author, 1996 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Human Development Department concerns, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Japan residency, 1996-1997 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Abigail Adams papers donation - IRS concerns, 1996-1998 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Cross listing courses with the history department, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - American College of Obstetricians and Gynaecologists Journal - permission to quote, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Ireland: Jacinta O'Brien, 1998-2002 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Signs- editor, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Thank you notes, 2005 (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence - general, 1997-2004 (Box 15, Folder 1)
- Series III. Lectures
  - Ithaca High School, "Elizabeth Cady Stanton Foundation:-Women in the Home :Past, Present and Future" (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Invitations not accepted, 1988-1993 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - The Clinton House, Ithaca - "The Victorian Era in Central New York", 1980-09 (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Human Development and Family Studies colloquium, 1980 (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Seneca Falls consortium, 1981-11 (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - New York State Council on the Arts, museum workshop program, 1982-11 (Box 5, Folder 22)
  - Six week summer institute - "Historians, Universities and Communities" at Cornell, 1982-07 (Box 5, Folder 23)
  - Conference on New York State History, 1983-06 (Box 5, Folder 24)
  - New York State History Seminar: "Ruines Girls: Family and Community Responses to Illegitimacy in Upstate New York 1890-1920", 1981 (Box 5, Folder 25)
  - American Association for the History of Medicine, 1988-05 (Box 5, Folder 26)
  - Nutrition, health and fitness working lunch for journalists in New York City, 1988-05 (Box 5, Folder 27)
  - University of Virginia Health Center, health sciences lecture series, 1988-11 (Box 5, Folder 28)
  - Rutgers, Princeton mental health training program, 1988-11 (Box 5, Folder 29)
  - Wells College, 1988 (Box 5, Folder 30)
  - Rochester eating disorders organization, 1987-01 (Box 5, Folder 31)
  - Syracuse University- department of psychiatry, 1989-05 (Box 5, Folder 32)
  - "Women and Food Group" at Cornell, 1989-06 (Box 5, Folder 33)
  - UNC, Duke, Davidson College, UBMC, 1989-09 (Box 5, Folder 34)
  - Rutgers Institute for Research on Women, 1989-11 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - UMBC culture and disease, 1989 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - SMA/SRA symposium, 1990-03 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Harvard, 1990-03 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - Pennsylvania consortium, 1990-04 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - Smith College, 1990-04 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Yale, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 40)
    Spring
  - American Historical Association, 1990 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Franklin and Marshall College, 1991-06 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Organization of American Historians, 1991-04 (Box 5, Folder 43)
  - University of Virginia, 1991-04 (Box 5, Folder 44)
  - Wesleyan University, 199-061 (Box 5, Folder 45)
  - RIT, 1991-07 (Box 5, Folder 46)
  - American Studies Association, 1991-10 (Box 5, Folder 47)
  - John Hopkins University, 1991-10 (Box 5, Folder 48)
  - Trustees Council, 1991-11 (Box 5, Folder 49)
  - Dartmouth, 1992-01 (Box 5, Folder 50)
  - Washington State Psychological Association, 1992-01 (Box 5, Folder 51)
  - American Educational Research Association Meeting, 1992-04 (Box 5, Folder 52)
  - Alice in Wonderland Conference, Amsterdam, 1992-06 (Box 5, Folder 53)
  - Society of American Archivists annual conference, 1992-09 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - University of Pittsburgh, 1992-09 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - Founders Day Dinner, 1992-09 (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - 20th anniversary of ACWS at Cornell, 1992-11 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Diary talks, 1992-1995 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Bryn Mawr, 1993-02 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - Brandeis, 1993-03 (Box 5, Folder 58)
  - American College of Obstetricians and Gynaecologists meeting, 1993-05 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - New York State Association of European Historians, 1993-10 (Box 5, Folder 60)
  - Hartwick College, 1993-10 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - University of Virginia, 1993-10 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - Vanderbilt University, 1993-11 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - Humanities Teachers Institute, 1993-1994 (Box 5, Folder 64)
  - Schlesinger Library Conference, 1994-03 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - Hartwick College, University of Virginia, Vanderbuilt, 1993 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - The Emergence of a Modern Disease: From Anorexia Mirabilis to Anorexia Nervosa (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - Canisius College, 1994-03 (Box 5, Folder 67)
  - University of Montana, Colgate University, Randolph Macon College, 1994-03-1994-04, 1997-03 (Box 5, Folder 68)
  - University of Rochester, 1994-06 (Box 5, Folder 69)
  - DeWitt Jr. High School, 1995-02 (Box 5, Folder 70)
  - SUNY Cortland, 1995-02 (Box 5, Folder 71)
  - Boston University, 1995-04 (Box 5, Folder 72)
  - Harvard, 1995-04 (Box 5, Folder 73)
  - Farewell to Hunter and Elizabeth Rawlings, 1995-05 (Box 5, Folder 74)
  - Union College, 1995-05 (Box 5, Folder 75)
  - Strong Museum, 1995-05 (Box 5, Folder 76)
  - Dickinson College, 1995-10 (Box 5, Folder 77)
  - Women's studies, 1995-11 (Box 5, Folder 78)
  - Renfrew Foundation Conference, 1995-11 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - International Conference on Eating Disorders, 1996-04 (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - "The Voices of Jewish Girls in Adolescent Diaries of the 1920s and 1950s"- DeWitt Historical Society, 1996-09 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - A social history of acne, 1996-09 (Box 5, Folder 81)
  - American Studies Association, 1996-11 (Box 5, Folder 82)
  - International Conference on Eating Disorders, Teleconference -"Women's Health Across Generations", 1996,1999 (Box 5, Folder 83)
  - "Female Sexuality: Past, Present and Future"- Wyeth Ayers Seminar, 1997-05 (Box 5, Folder 84)
  - Trinity College, 1997-09 (Box 5, Folder 85)
  - Women's health update media seminar" The Female Body Image Weighing Heavily On Our Health", 1997-10 (Box 5, Folder 86)
  - SUNY Cortland, American Studies Association Panel, 1997-10 (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - Japan talk, 1997-11 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Family Impact Seminar, 1997-12 (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - Friends of Libraries USA, Mt. Holyoke, Arizona State University West, Milton Academy, 1998-01-1998-03 (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - University of Illinois, New Jersey Education Association, Planned Parenthood of CT, 1998-04, 1998-05 (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - The National Coalition of Girls Schools, Jewish Museum, 1998-06 (Box 5, Folder 91)
  - "The Stuff of Women's History" conference, 1998-08 (Box 5, Folder 92)
  - University of Louisville, Williams College, 1998-09 (Box 5, Folder 93)
  - Heinz conference`, 1998-09 (Box 5, Folder 94)
  - Thiel College, Charter Hospital, Wi, court appointed special advocate, 1998-11 (Box 5, Folder 95)
  - Charter Behavioral Health System, Nashville, TN, 1998-11 (Box 5, Folder 96)
  - University of Michigan, New York State School Psychologists Conference, Writer's Harvest, 1998-10 (Box 5, Folder 97)
  - Drew University, Miss Porter's School, CT, Greenwich Academy, 1998-11 (Box 5, Folder 98)
  - Introduction for Betty Friedan dinner, 1998-12 (Box 5, Folder 99)
  - Children's Hospital, Columbus, Ohio, 1998-12 (Box 5, Folder 100)
  - Colgate, University of Colorado, Cornell Alumnae Branch, 1999-02 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Katherine Delmar Burke School, Hamlin School, Westridge School, 1999-02 (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Huntington Library, Glendale Community College, 1999-02 (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Princeton, PCCW, 1999-02, 1999-03 (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Indiana University Northwest, Marlborough School, Hockaday School Dallas, 1999-03 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Texas Women's University, Montgomery CC, Wells College, 1999-03 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Cornell Alumni Association of North Texas, Chatham Hall VA, Temple University, 1999-04 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Organization of American Historians and University of Buffalo, 1999-04 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Emory, Aware Foundation: "Thought Leader's Conference", 1999-05 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Adolescent Wellness and Reproductive Education meeting, 1999-05 (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - University of Louisville, Williams College, 1999-09 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Illinois Caucus for Adolescent Health, 1999-09 (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - University of Rochester, 1999-10 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Barnard College, 1999-10 (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - AASL American Library Association, 1999-11 (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - University of Richmond, 1999-11 (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - St. Joseph's Medical Center, 2000-02 (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Hamilton College, 2000-02 (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - Western Maryland College, 2000-02 (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - Spence School, Metro Health Medical Center Conference, Ohio, William Paterson University, 2000-02, 2000-05, 2001-03 (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - Marshall University, 2000-03 (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Metro Health Medical Center, Cleveland, 2000-05 (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - Bassett-Cooperstown, 2000-08 (Box 6, Folder 22)
  - International Association of Eating Disorders Professionals Foundation, Florida, 2000-08 (Box 6, Folder 23)
  - Research Network on Adolescent Development and Juvenile Justice, 2000-10 (Box 6, Folder 24)
  - Stony Brook, 2000-10 (Box 6, Folder 25)
  - International Association of Eating Disorders Professionals Foundation, Swathmore, Tompkins County Library, 2000-08, 2000-11 (Box 6, Folder 26)
  - Bowden College, MacArthur Foundation Network Meeting, Bucknell, Ithaca Childcare Center, 2000-09-2000-11 (Box 6, Folder 27)
  - Syracuse Symposium, Parents Council of Washington, 2002-01, 2001-03 (Box 6, Folder 28)
  - Barnard Summit, 2000-08, 2003-04 (Box 6, Folder 29)
  - Reunion Talk for Library Associates, 2001-06 (Box 6, Folder 30)
  - Centennial of the College, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 31)
  - PCCW, 2001-03 (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - University of New England,,Muhlenberg College, 2002-01, 2002-03 (Box 6, Folder 32)
  - Bassett Hospital, 2002-10 (Box 6, Folder 33)
  - Engagements, 2002-2003 (Box 6, Folder 34)
  - Organization of American Historians, Sarah Lawrence, 2003-04, 2002-10 (Box 6, Folder 35)
  - Cranbrook Schools, 2003-04 (Box 6, Folder 36)
  - Colgate University, 2003-04 (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Public History: Shedding the Academic Girdle, 2003-09 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Cornell club, Minnesota Historical Society, 2003-10 (Box 6, Folder 38)
  - University of Minnesota, Northwestern- Cornell Club, Clarement, 2003-10 (Box 6, Folder 39)
  - Davis and Elkins College, 2003-10 (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - University of Virginia, 2003-11 (Box 6, Folder 40)
  - Nazareth College, Horizons Theatre, 2004-02, 2004-03 (Box 6, Folder 41)
  - Libe Cafe, 2004-02 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Binghamton University, 2004-04 (Box 6, Folder 42)
  - Renfrew, 2004-06 (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - Framingham State, Central CT State, 2004-10 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Daytona Community College, Stetson University, 2004-11 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Stetson College, 2004-11 (Box 16, Folder 14)
  - RIT, 2004-12 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Cortland State, Vanderbilt, Hobart William Smith, 2005-03 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - New Tier High School- Illinois, prevent child abuse conference, 2005-04 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Trinity College symposium, 2005-09 (Box 6, Folder 48)
  - Mt. Holyoke, Horizons Theatre, 2005-10 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Renfrew Center Foundation Conference for Professionals, 2005-11 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - High school talk, 2006-01 (Box 16, Folder 15)
  - Herkimer Community College, 2006-04 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - University of New Hampshire, 2006-04 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - OAH, Pennsylvania, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 53)
  - WSSEDO, 2006-04 (Box 6, Folder 54)
  - Conference at the University of Ottawa, 2006-11 (Box 6, Folder 55)
  - Radcliffe - Gender at the Table, 2007-04 (Box 16, Folder 16)
  - Proctor and Gamble, 2007-10 (Box 16, Folder 17)
  - Cortland, UNH, 2007 (Box 16, Folder 18)
  - Lycoming College, 2008-10 (Box 16, Folder 19)
  - Ithaca College, 2009-02 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Holyoke College, 2009-03 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - University of Nebraska, 2009-04 (Box 16, Folder 22)
  - University of Pennsylvania, 2011-04 (Box 16, Folder 23)
  - Monmouth College, 2012-10 (Box 16, Folder 24)
  - Dickinson College, 2014-04 (Box 16, Folder 25)
  - Cornell reunion, 2014-06 (Box 16, Folder 26)
  - Dartmouth College, 2014-09 (Box 16, Folder 27)
  - Independent Schools - New York State Psychologists, no date (Box 16, Folder 28)
  - Bookery remarks, no date (Box 16, Folder 29)
  - McCord Museum, no date (Box 16, Folder 30)
  - ALA in New Orleans, no date (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Various lectures given by Joan and a program from the play "The Body Project", 1979-2009 (Box 15, Folder 2)
- Series IV. Teaching Material
  - Salary information, 1989-1997 (Box 16, Folder 32)
  - Syllabi- other colleges, 1997-1998 (Box 6, Folder 56)
  - Courses, 1970-1979 (Box 6, Folder 57)
  - Human Development and Family Studies 150 (Box 6, Folder 58)
  - Handouts (Box 6, Folder 59)
  - "History of Childhood in the United States"- assignments Human Development and Family Studies 155, 1980-1989 (Box 6, Folder 60)
  - "History of Childhood in the United States"- slide show, 1980-1989 (Box 6, Folder 61)
  - "History of Childhood in the United States"- subject files Human Development 241 (Box 6, Folder 62)
  - "History of Childhood in the United States" - readings Human Development 241 (Box 6, Folder 63)
  - Dr. Spock video - Human Development 241 (Box 6, Folder 64)
  - "History of Childhood in the United States" - readings and exams Human Development 241 (Box 6, Folder 65)
  - "History of Childhood in the United States" Human Development 241, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 66)
  - "History of Childhood in the United States" Human Development 241, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - "History of Childhood in the United States" Postman Material Human Development 241, 1998-2001 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - Subject Files C. S Miller- Postman Response (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - "History of Childhood in the United States" Human Development 241, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 71)
    Fall
  - "History of Childhood in the United States" Human Development 241, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - "History of Childhood in the United States" - course packet Human Development 241, 2001 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - "History of Women in the Professions" syllabi and study Human Development 258, 1979-1984 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - "History of Women in the Professions", 1985-1990 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - "History of Women in the Professions"- handouts and study guides Human Development 258, 1990-1992 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - "History of Women in the Professions"- handouts and study guides Human Development 258, 1995 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - "History of Women in the Professions"- lecture notes- Dr. Zay Human Development 258, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - "History of Women in the Professions"- exams Human Development 258, 1979-1995 (Box 6, Folder 79)
  - "History of Women in the Professions"- bibliography Human Development 258, 1992 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - "History of Women in the Professions" Human Development 258, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 81)
  - "History of Women in the Professions"- bibliography Human Development 258, 1998 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - "History of Women in the Professions"- bibliography Human Development 258, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Women in the Professions (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Women in the Professions- Virginia Woolf (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Women in the Professions - publications (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - "American Families in Historical Perspective" Human Development 359, 1981 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - "American Families in Historical Perspective" Human Development 359, 1982 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    Fall and Spring